[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What does the acronym \"C++\" stand for?",
    "answers": [
      "Computer Plus",
      "Complex Plus",
      "C Plus Plus",
      "Coding Plus Plus"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax for including the standard input/output library in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "#include <iostrm>",
      "include <stdio.h>",
      "#include <iostream>",
      "include <stdlib>"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of the `main` function in a C++ program?",
    "answers": [
      "To declare variables",
      "To perform calculations",
      "To receive input from the user",
      "Program execution starts from here"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "How do you declare a variable in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "variable x;",
      "x = variable;",
      "int x;",
      "x is variable;"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which operator is used for performing division in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "*",
      "/",
      "%",
      "+"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What is the output of `cout << \"Hello, \" << \"World!\";` in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "Hello, World!",
      "Hello,",
      "World!",
      "Error"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "How do you comment a single line in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "// This is a comment",
      "/* This is a comment */",
      "# This is a comment",
      "-- This is a comment"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct way to declare and initialize an array in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "array = [1, 2, 3];",
      "int array[] = {1, 2, 3};",
      "array(1, 2, 3);",
      "int array(1, 2, 3);"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What is the purpose of the `cin` object in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "Output to console",
      "Input from console",
      "String concatenation",
      "Mathematical calculations"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which header file should be included to use the `cin` and `cout` objects in C++?",
    "answers": [
      "<stdio.h>",
      "<iostream>",
      "<math.h>",
      "<stdlib.h>"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  }
]
